Guide to the Frank A. Pearson papers, 1923-1965
Pearson, Frank A. papers, 1923-1965
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Frank a. Pearson papers, 1923-1965.
21-10-453
Frank A.(Frank Ashmore), Pearson 1887-
28.4 linear ft.
Correspondence, publications, manuscripts, and photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Professional correspondence, manuscripts by Pearson and Warren; notes; speeches and publications; lecture notes on prices; research material on cream; statistics; notes and drafts and related correspondence on world hunger, the price of gold, and foodstuffs. Also, photographs and slides of Cornell and other scenes and subjects.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Prices and Statistics, New York State College of Agriculture.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Professional correspondence concerning prices, statistics, and economics; correspondence and notes on the career of George Frederick Warren; mss. by Pearson and Warren; notes on a trip to England and other subjects; speeches and publications; lecture notes on prices; research material on cream; statistics (30 v.); notes and drafts and related correspondence on world hunger, the price of gold, and foodstuffs. Also, photographs and slides of Cornell and other scenes and subjects.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Pearson, Frank A.1887-; Warren, George F.(George Frederick), 1874-1938.
Subjects:
Agriculture--Economic aspects.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Color slides.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Includes collection 21-10-814.
CONTAINER LIST
- Warren G.F.: gold: News Clippings (Box 1)
- Warren G.F.: biography by F.A. Pearson, all notes and 3 editions of final manuscript: Farm Economics Article (Box 1)
- Warren G.F.: correspondence with F.A. Pearson only, 1922-1938 (Box 1)
- F.A. Pearson correspondence (Box 1)
- James B. Sumner (Nobel Prize Winner) and F.A. Pearson relations, 1954-1955 (Box 1)
- F.A. Pearson (Box 1)
  Dr. Tucker, General Motors World Index of Wholesale Prices
  London trip September 1934, Sir Henry Deterding and Inflation (Shell Oil)
  Price Plans
- Warren Correspondence and Notes (Box 2)
- Addresses by F.A. Pearson, 1929-1937 (Box 3, Volume 1-5)
- Addresses by F.A. Pearson, 1936- (Box 4, Volume 6-14)
- Addresses by F.A. Pearson (Box 5, Volume 15-22)
- Addresses by F.A. Pearson (Box 6, Volume 23-31)
- Warren G.F. and F.A. Pearson: Major Works (Box 7)
  Wholesale prices on U.S. for 135 years monthly
  Interrelations of supply and price for Bul. 466
  Major project curve in fitting to find a curve that was logical and mathematically correct.
- F.A. Pearson's Lecture Notes on Prices: Gold, Cycles, Cycles Combinations, Cycles-Pepper, Coffee, Cocoa, Livestock (Box 8-9)
- Correspondence, Farm Economics Speeches (Box 10)
- F.A. Pearson's correspondence with former Warren students about Warren (Box 11)
- Warren's quips collected by F.A. Pearson (Box 11)
- F.A. Pearson's Tabulation of Warren's articles (Box 11)
- F.A. Pearson's Tabulation of conferences and committees in which Warren participated, 1912-1938 (Box 11)
- F.A. Pearson's Correspondence (Box 12)
  Pepper: Correspondence with Thomas W. Phelps of Francis I. Dupont and Co., 1941-1947
  General Motors
  Mr. Niece; General Motors
  Leffingwell; J. P. Morgan; I. Bennett, John Scoville, Harding Hoover, Kansas, Keith Murray Ohio Farm Bureau, Frank Platt Paarlberg
- F. A. Pearson's Early Work at the University of Illinois and Cornell (Box 13)
  McHenry County Survey
  Illinois Milk Report
- F. A. Pearson's works at Cornell, 1933-1957 (Box 14)
- "Farm Economics", edited by: Warren and Pearson, 1923-1938 (Box 15)
  #1-106=8
- "Farm Economics", edited by: Pearson and Myers, 1928-1957 (Box 15)
  #107-211=8
- Books By: Warren and Pearson, Pearson and Paarlburg, Pearson and Harper, Pearson and Vial on World Food Prices (Box 15)
- Pepper; Interstate Commission-Chicago-North Western Railroad Testimony by F.A. Pearson (Box 15)
- Wartime Letters of Corporal F.A. Pearson III to his father and mother, June 1943-October 1945 (Box 15)
- Lecture Notes on Prices (Box 16)
  Gnats and Prices: 3-legged stool
  Index numbers: history: unweights, weighted, old notes
  Effect of Prices on Production, Effect of Production on Prices
  Cash and future Prices
  Function of Price
  Value and Price
  Commodity Dollar
  Farm Supports
  Investments
  New Theories
- A Study of Prices of All Spices-Never Completed (Box 17)
- German Commission (Box 17)
- Speeches-F.A. Pearson and Don Paarlberg, 1944-1946 (Box 18)
- Hoover Chicago Milk, 1917-1919 (Box 18)
- Stencils- F.A. Pearson, June 9, 1970 (Box 18)
- Published Articles by Warren, Pearson, and both (Box 19)
- Warren Story, 2nd, 3rd, 4th, and 5th editions (Box 20)
- Prices of dairy products- Pearson and E.E. Vial (Box 21)
- The "Bull-Shit" article (Box 21)
- F.A Pearson's last address, February 24, 1958 (Box 21)
- Pearson and Paarlberg: Starvation, truths, half truths, and untruths (Box 21)
- Large Black and White Prints, 11 x 14 inches, mounted 16 x 20 inches
- Coeds A-B (Box 24)
- Coeds C-E (Box 25)
- Coeds F-Hi (Box 26)
- Coeds Ho-J (Box 27)
- Coeds K-L (Box 28)
- Coeds M-O (Box 29)
- Coeds P (Box 30)
- Coeds R (Box 31)
- Coeds S, except Stolp (Box 32)
- Coeds T-V and Stolp (Box 33)
- Coeds W-Z (Box 34)
- Boy-Girl A-D (Box 35)
- Boy-Girl E-H, except Horn, Hurd, Holden (Box 36)
- Boy-Girl H-L, including Horn, Hurd, Holden (Box 37)
- Boy-Girl M-P (Box 38)
- Boy-Girl R-S (Box 39)
- Boy-Girl Sch-V (Box 40)
- Boys A-J (Box 41)
- Boys K-P (Box 42)
- Boys R-Z (Box 43)
- Snow (Box 44)
- Water (Box 45)
- Old Men A-G (Box 46)
- Old Men H-S (Box 47)
- Professors (Box 48)
- Babies (Box 49-50)
- Teenagers (Box 51)
- Campus, Summer (Box 52-53)
- Campus, Winter (Box 54)
- Water (Box 55-56)
- Farm, Summer (Box 57)
- Farm, Winter (Box 58)
- Buildings (Box 59)
- Flowers (Box 60)
- Roads and Tombstones (Box 61)
- Trees and Woods (Box 62)
- Hands and Miscellaneous (Box 63)
- Haze (Box 64)
- Animals and Birds (Box 65)
- Small Black and White Prints and Negatives
- Coeds A-B, Envelope 1 (Box 66)
- Coeds D-E, Envelope 2 (Box 66)
- Coeds F-Hi, Envelope 3 (Box 66)
- Coeds Ho-J, Envelope 4 (Box 66)
- Coeds K-L, Envelope 5 (Box 66)
- Coeds M-O, Envelope 6 (Box 66)
- Coeds P, Envelope 7 (Box 66)
- Coeds R, Envelope 8 (Box 66)
- Coeds S, except Stolp, Envelope 9 (Box 66)
- Coeds T-V and Stolp, Envelope 10 (Box 66)
- Coeds W-Z, Envelope 11 (Box 66)
- Boy-Girl A-D, Envelope 12 (Box 66)
- Boy-Girl E-H, except Horn, Hurd, Horreman, and Holder, Envelope 13 (Box 66)
- Boy-Girl H-L, Envelope 14 (Box 66)
- Boy-Girl M-P, Envelope 15 (Box 66)
- Boy-Girl R-T, Envelope 16 (Box 66)
- Boy-Girl Sch-Z, Envelope 17 (Box 66)
- Boys A-J, Envelope 18 (Box 66)
- Boys K-P, Envelope 19 (Box 66)
- Boys R-Z, Envelope 20 (Box 66)
- Students-Snow, Envelope 21 (Box 66)
- Students-Water, Envelope 22 (Box 67)
- Old Men A-C, Envelope 23 (Box 67)
- Old Men D-S, Envelope 24 (Box 67)
- Professors, Envelope 25 (Box 67)
- Babies-Pearson, Envelope 26 (Box 67)
- Babies, including some Pearson, Family, and Ladies, Envelope 27 (Box 67)
- Teenagers, Envelope 28 (Box 67)
- Campus- Water and Miscellaneous, Envelope 31A (Box 67)
- Campus-Water and Miscellaneous, Envelope 31B (Box 67)
- Farm-Summer, Envelope 32 (Box 67)
- Farm-Winter, Envelope 33 (Box 67)
- Buildings, Envelope 34 (Box 67)
- Flowers, Envelope 35 (Box 67)
- Mountains, Roads and Tombstones, Envelope 36 (Box 67)
- Hands and Miscellaneous, Envelope 38 (Box 67)
- Haze, Envelope 39 (Box 67)
- Small Black and White Prints and Negatives, Not Enlarged
- Coeds A-B, Envelope 1 (Box 68)
- Coeds C-E, Envelope 2 (Box 68)
- Coeds E-H, Envelope 3 (Box 68)
- Coeds Ho-J, Envelope 4 (Box 68)
- Coeds K-L, Envelope 5 (Box 68)
- Coeds M-O, Envelope 6 (Box 68)
- Coeds P, Envelope 7 (Box 68)
- Coeds P-R, Envelope 8 (Box 68)
- Coeds S, Envelope 9 (Box 68)
- Coeds T-V, Envelope 10 (Box 68)
- Coeds W-Z, Envelope 11 (Box 68)
- Boy-Girl A-D, Envelope 12 (Box 68)
- Boy-Girl E-H, Envelope 13 (Box 68)
- Boy-Girl H-L, Envelope 14 (Box 68)
- Boy-Girl M-P, Envelope 15 (Box 68)
- Boy-Girl R-T, Envelope 16 (Box 69)
- Boy-Girl U-Z, Envelope 17 (Box 69)
- Boys A-D, Envelope 18A (Box 69)
- Boys E-D, Envelope 18B (Box 69)
- Boys K-P, Envelope 19 (Box 69)
- Boys R-Z, Envelope 20 (Box 69)
- Students, Envelope 21 (Box 69)
- Old Men, Envelope 24 (Box 69)
- Professors, Envelope 25 (Box 69)
- Ladies, Envelope 27 (Box 69)
- Teenagers, Envelope 28 (Box 69)
- Water, Envelope 31B (Box 69)
- Farm, Envelope 34 (Box 69)
- Buildings, Envelope (Box 69)
- Flowers, Envelope 35 (Box 69)
- Hands, Envelope 38 (Box 69)
- Haze, Envelope 39 (Box 69)
- Animals, Envelope 40 (Box 69)
- Animals, Envelope 40 (Box 74)
- Animals, Envelope 40 (Box 69)
- Animals, Envelope 40 (Box 69)